这一章节的《 Wolfram 笔记本介绍》的内容
是使用笔记本进行演示
例如以幻灯片的形式显示笔记本
这里是一个典型的幻灯片的例子
它本质上只是一个笔记本
并且每次显示一张幻灯片
你可以通过点击显示屏右上角的这个按钮
(-)
待对照！！！然后在弹出的菜单中选择" "来结束幻灯片放映
这样会在工作格式下显示同一个笔记本
这个笔记本用来创建幻灯片
This working slideshow notebook
和其他的笔记本几乎一样
不过有两个基本的区别
一是两张幻灯片之间有幻灯片分隔线 (Slide Break) 单元
二是是笔记本顶部会显示创作工具栏
！！不通顺：创作工具栏是一个停靠在顶端的单元
The authoring toolbar is a docked cell
带有常见操作的控件
例如插入新幻灯片页面、开始演示
The authoring toolbar and the Slide Break cells
还有其他所有能让笔记本能够作为创建幻灯片环境的功能
(-)
是在 stylesheet. 中设置的
这个笔记本的 stylesheet
是在 PresenterTools 子菜单中选择的
该子菜单位于 Format ► Stylesheet
All of the stylesheets in the PresenterTools submenu
包括创建幻灯片所需的所有选项
实际上  任何一个笔记本都可以做成幻灯片
只需要选择 PresenterTools stylesheets 中的一个选项
并且插入幻灯片分隔线单元
例如  这里是和刚才同样的笔记本
但是没有幻灯片分界线单元
并且采用的是 normal Default stylesheet,
也就是在 stylesheet 子菜单中选中的项目
菜单的下方是 PresenterTools 子菜单
再下方有一个名为 SlideShow 的子菜单
这里包含的 SlideShow 子菜单是为了
提供对旧版本幻灯片系统的支持
它已经在 Wolfram 笔记本中存在多年了
(-)
但是本节课程是关于更新的 PresenterTools 系统的
它是旧系统的增强版
要把笔记本做成幻灯片
我们需要选择 PresenterTools stylesheets 中的一个选项
一个便捷的插入幻灯片分界线的方式
是首先打开创作工具栏
它可以通过在“格式”菜单的“显示屏环境”子菜单内将屏幕环境改为 Slideshow Working 来调出
(-)
(-)2
然后点击创作工具栏上的“插入新幻灯片”按钮
打开一个小的浮动菜单
提供插入不带背景的幻灯片分隔或带背景的幻灯片分隔两个选项
无论哪种选择都会插入幻灯片中断
它被一个新的具有名为幻灯片导航栏的格式的单元所标记
which is marked by a new cell with a cell style called slideshow navigation bar.
(-)
你也可以通过从幻灯片其他位置复制粘贴幻灯片分界线单元来创建新幻灯片
(-)2
例如  我们可以选中幻灯片分界线单元
和下方的 Section 单元
接着复制所选单元  再将它们粘贴在笔记本其他部位
来获得新的一页幻灯片
编辑幻灯片的方式还包括删除幻灯片
或删除幻灯片分界线
例如  为了删除刚才新增的幻灯片页面
我们可以选中幻灯片分界线单元
和幻灯片的内容然后删掉所选项
另外一种在整个笔记本中插入幻灯片分界线的方式
(-)
是单击创作工具栏上的 Slide Break Defaults  按钮
这会打开一个对话框
在这个对话框中你可以根据单元格的样式选择幻灯片分割线
例如  选择对话框中的 Section
然后点击设置来在笔记本中每一个 Section 单元前插入幻灯片分界线
(-)
！！不通顺：如果笔记本已经组织成章节 If the notebook is already organized into sections,
这是把笔记本转换成幻灯片的捷径
相比转换默认的笔记本到幻灯片
(-)
在多数情况下
创建新幻灯片最方便的方法
是从“文件”菜单下 “新建” ► Presenter Notebook 开始
(-)
这会打开一个对话框
for choosing from the same set of PresenterTools stylesheets,
在这里它们叫做主题
从这个对话框理你还可以选择
各种预设字体格式和配色方案
做出一些选择后
单击“创建”按钮以获得一个幻灯片模板
带有所选的 PresenterTools stylesheet
显示屏自动环境设置为 Slideshow Working
创作工具栏显示在顶部  一些幻灯片
已经被填充了通用的内容
这一笔记本可以和其他任何笔记本一样被编辑
以填充幻灯片的内容
创作工具栏上的一些按钮
是控制字体和样式的通用部件
它们可以用于任何笔记本
例如  这个按钮会打开选择单元样式的菜单
(-)
这与在“格式”菜单的 Style 子菜单中的可选项相同
单元格式菜单旁边
是一个有趣的按钮  它可以被用来
将字体设置应用到所有具有相同格式的单元
例如
在我们设置这一文本单元使用大字号、粗体后
点击这个按钮就会有
将这些选项应用到该笔记本里所有文本单元的效果
(-)
你也可以
This worked by editing the private stylesheet
for this notebook.
例如
选择“格式”菜单下 Edit Stylesheet
会显示本笔记本内的 private stylesheet
和新的本地样式定义
这些定义为文本指定了大的粗体字
你可以通过直接编辑样式表来达到同样的效果
(-)
所以在创作工具栏中的按钮
基本上
用于一键修改样式表
有一个按钮是值得说几句的  按下这个按钮
会打开一个浮动菜单
用来调大或调小字号
要描述该菜单的作用  我们需要首先介绍一下
所有 PresenterTools stylesheets 的功能
它可以根据窗口大小动态调整内容的尺寸
(-)
例如  如果窗口的大小改变了
文本的字号也会随之改变  图片也有同样的效果
几乎所有笔记本中其他的内容
都会随之窗口的大小而改变
你可以在任何一个笔记本中获得同样的效果
只需要调整字体、图片等的缩放比例
但是与其他大部分 stylesheets 不同
在 RresenterTools stylesheets 中所有关于缩放的选项
都已经是这个 stylesheet 的一部分
像这样的动态缩放
通常情况下很有帮助
譬如在你想扩大演示界面的窗口
或者是在不同窗口大小的显示系统上进行演示的情况下
(-)
现在让我们回到字体大小的问题上
如果字体大小通过选中一些文字
然后在“格式”菜单的 Size 子菜单选则某个字号的方式指定
(-)
那么当窗口的大小发生变化时   该文本的大小将保持不变
因为这种大小设置优先于
stylesheet 的动态缩放系统
创作工具栏上的字体大小按钮
的工作方式不同
例如  选中一些字符然后在创作工具栏的浮动菜单中选择一个新的大小
(-)
会使选中的文字的字号按所选步长的比例放大或缩小
to be scaled up or down by the chosen number of steps,
(-)
and the resized text does change size
based on the size of the window.
Similar issues also apply to images and to graphics.
For example, selecting this image
changes the authoring toolbar
to show a button for locking the current size of the image
or letting the size of the image change
with the size of the window.
Choosing Lock to current size
sets the image size option for that selection
to the current fixed value,
which results in an image that, like the text shown earlier,
remains at a fixed size
when the size of the window is changed.
So while dynamic resizing is the default,
you can get fixed sizes by specifying sizes
for individual selections.
Other buttons in the authoring toolbar
include the Start Presentation button,
which is the button to click to start the presentation,
which we will do in a moment.
The first button below the Start Presentation button
brings up a palette of buttons
showing the outline of the slideshow.
These buttons can be clicked
to navigate between slides in the notebook.
This palette also includes a refresh button
to update the palette if slides are added or removed.
The button next to that opens the Side Notes palette,
which provides a way of adding notes
that are intended for the presenter
and that will be shown in this palette,
but that are not displayed in the presentation.
To add a side note,
click the Add note to slide button,
which inserts a cell called a SideNote cell
into the slideshow notebook.
This cell can be edited just like any other cell.
Clicking the refresh button updates the Side Notes palette
with any new side notes.
Clicking this last button opens a popup menu.
Choosing Style Palette from that menu
opens a palette of buttons
like the buttons in the authoring toolbar.
Choosing Presentation Controls
opens a dialog box for customizing the computer keys
for navigating between slides.
Choosing Theme Options opens the same dialog box
that was used initially for choosing a stylesheet.
So if you wanted to change the stylesheet
from the stylesheet that was chosen initially,
you can do that here,
or equivalently, by choosing a different stylesheet
from the Stylesheet submenu.
For example, this changes the fonts
and the color scheme of the presentation
by changing the stylesheet.
To start the slideshow,
we can click the Start Presentation button.
At the end of the Start Presentation button
is a popup menu for other screen environments.
Scrolling Presentation gives a display
for scrolling through the slides
rather than clicking from slide to slide,
and Slideshow Presentation
switches the screen environment to Slideshow Presentation,
which removes the authoring toolbar
and the Slide Break cells and the SideNote cells.
Clicking the main Start Presentation button
does all of that
and also switches to full-screen display.
After the presentation is started,
you can move between slides
using keys on the computer keyboard
or the corresponding keys on a separate controller.
Within the slideshow, there is a button
in the upper-right corner of the window
that can be clicked
to open a popup menu with other controls.
There are choices here for moving to the first slide
or to the next slide and so on.
Choosing Toggle Navigation Bar adds on-screen controls
at the top of the window for moving between slides.
Choosing Toggle Style Tools opens the same palette
of style controls that was shown earlier.
In Slideshow Working screen environment,
this palette isn't usually needed since the same controls
are available in the authoring toolbar,
but here this palette provides a way of editing the slideshow
from within the actual presentation,
rather than from the working notebook environment.
Choosing Side Notes
opens the Side Notes palette to show side notes,
which you could display on a different monitor
or on a separate tablet or other device.
You can also click within this palette
to move between slides.
Choosing Slide Outline opens the Slide Outline palette
that was shown earlier,
which provides yet another way of moving between slides.
Going beyond a basic slideshow like this,
there's an unlimited range of possibilities
for what is displayed in a presentation
and for how that display is controlled.
To illustrate some of the possibilities,
consider this animation,
which is used for illustrating a topic
that comes up during this particular presentation.
During a presentation,
the presenter can control this animation
using the controls in the display.
There are, however, situations where it would be better
to have the controls somewhere else,
such as in a separate controller.
There are several ways to do that,
one of which is shown here.
This example shows a display in the presentation
that depends on a dynamically updated variable
and a button in a separate notebook
for controlling the value of that variable.
This allows the presentation
to be controlled by a separate controller,
which is useful in settings
where it is inconvenient for the presenter
to click on buttons in the display.
Wolfram Notebooks support a whole collection of features
for programmatic control of the display,
so it is possible to design presentations
with complex animations or sequences of images,
and to program all of that in advance
so that it can be shown during the presentation
with the click of a button on an off-screen controller.
That's the end of the examples for this section.
In the Wolfram documentation, you can find more information
by searching for presentations or slideshows,
and in particular from this page
on preparing and giving presentations,
which includes links to workflow guides like this one,
with step-by-step instructions
for the operations that came up in this section.